First and foremost, I don't want to keep
our special guest waiting, so
her name is Ms. Amanda Seales. She's an
actress, a comedian, an activist, and
very, very vocal out in these streets.
You saw her recently in the Jubilee
debate where she debated 20 black
conservatives. Let's go ahead and bring
her in. Welcome, Amanda. Welcome, Savvy
Savs. Can I Can I tell you something off
top, though? I hate being called an
actress.
Do you know a lot of actors?
I do not.
They're a different kind of crazy.
It's a different It's a different type
of crazy. Like comedians, we're crazy,
too, but it's a different kind of crazy.
Actors, I be like, "Ooh, child, don't go
I'm able to act." But
and I and I've left and I've left that
life. I've left that life, Sabrina. Or
why do I keep I I keep wanting to call
you your full Sabrina. Can I call you
Sabrina? I feel like it's such a like
eloquent name.
You can. Most people call me Sabrina.
It's It's interesting. Outside of
YouTube, most people call me Sabrina.
Yeah, I feel like it's like one of those
names. It's like, "No, give us all the
syllables. Sabrina."
Well, Amanda, oh my gosh, we have so
much to discuss. I have been LOOKING FOR
YOU.
TELL THEM TELL THEM TELL THEM WHAT YOU
FOUND, THOUGH. Tell them what you found.
I got to tell everybody. You guys know
I'm not the best on Instagram, and I
know you guys have gotten on me about
this before and you said, "You need to
be You need to check IG." And I'm just
terrible with it. And so, what I found
out is that Amanda reached out to me on
Instagram. And I didn't see it because
I'm I'm rarely on there, and I wasn't
even checking like Instagram messages.
And I saw that, AND I WAS LIKE, "WHOA! I
DIDN'T KNOW I DIDN'T KNOW I did not
know." But I was like
>> been extended.
It's true. It is It is true. I was like,
"Oh my gosh, I didn't know." Yeah, I was
I was Everybody had kept telling me they
said, "Can you please bring on Amanda
Seales?" And I was like, "I don't know
how to find her." And so, yeah, I'm I'm
trying to get her.
>> to So, you got to come over to to Views
from AmandaLand, to my show, too. Sorry,
my locs are doing what they want to do
tonight, and I'm like
>> I I'd love I'd love to. I I got to get
started with the 2024 presidential
election. So,
those of us that decided not to support
I I did not support Kamala Harris. I
voted third party.
>> at you about this. They are still mad at
me, and I know they're still mad at you,
too, because you were very vocal about
that Kamala Harris was not bringing
forward the policies that are needed in
this country right now. And then also,
her aligning herself with Liz Cheney.
Now, people are saying, "Don't you guys
feel bad for not voting for Kamala
Harris?" And I want to get your take
about that. How do you feel about that?
The the type of
uh anger that was thrown your way for
not wanting to advocate for, and as they
said at that time, a black woman.
Forgive them, Father, for they know not
what
They do.
I mean, that's really at this point um
there's a certain level of of
I don't want to even say grace, cuz
that's not the word I'm looking for, but
it's just like I understand that they
are
not knowledgeable in a way that has been
really effective for the Democratic
Party. Like, there has been a very
deep-seated effort for the past 40
years, a disinformation campaign that
has really kept black folks in a
chokehold. I was one of those black
folks that was in that chokehold,
thinking that this is the only option,
and so all of our eggs needed to be put
into this basket. Um
and I remember in 2020 with with Joe
Biden, I was also very like
um
I was also very critical about Joe Biden
and they all got on me and people
started attacking me publicly and
privately about how dare you. I remember
this guy Isaac Hayes III was like, you
know, this is the most dangerous black
woman in America. Y'all also be giving
me way too much like status.
Um
and to be quite honest, they got to me.
Like the the
the blacks got to me and made me feel
like I was anti us if I wasn't pro
Biden.
And I folded and over the next four
years, I then watched how there was
nothing being done to prevent us being
in this same situation again. And I
found that to be very disconcerting. Why
are we now in 2024 and we're in the same
back against the walls, it's a crisis,
the boogeyman is going to get us
situation that should have been dealt
with and it should have been addressed
on day two after
Biden was elected. And I said, I'm not
going to be a part of this again. I'm
not What I What I mean by a part of this
is and I remember I called Charlamagne
and I had texted Roland Martin about
this and I said
I believe that this go around
there needs to be a really concerted
effort with connecting with voters in an
honest way instead of doing this
manipulative thing that ends up
happening where it's like, oh, they're
not smart enough to understand the
nuances and the challenging that needs
to be done. So, we're just going to
paint this pretty picture of just vote
for so-and-so and don't worry about
anything else. I said, we're dealing
with folks who are a lot more mindful
now.
They are a lot more aware of not just
their feelings, but of the world. Like
we're not dealing with such a ignorant
populace and it really doesn't serve us
to move this way. And um you know they
chose to go the way they chose but I
stuck to my guns which was first of all
I don't endorse candidates so even with
Joe Biden it was like
I'M NOT SAYING BUT THIS IS THE OPTION.
BUT THEN I GOT REALLY YOU KNOW AND I
ALSO met Kamala and I think that's the
other part of it like a lot of folks are
speaking from
what they've interpreted of a person and
I'm speaking from what I've experienced.
And when I spoke to Kamala she did not
express to me any interest in
actually trying to deal with
things head on that
are affecting the black community
specifically racism institutionally
systemically legislatively and that
really shook me
um
and then
>> So she wait she she said she said she
was not she said that to you she wasn't
interested? She said to me I said
I said
we don't trust you.
And she said well why why why why why?
And I said well okay let's start with
the way that you speak about racism. You
know you are constantly speaking about
racism as if it's something from the
past or as if it's only associated with
slavery. You were just on The View
saying we're dealing with the vestiges
of racism which means the remnants of
racism when really no racism is very
present and it's gaining steam and it's
ability to be you know ruling folks
lives and she said well what do you
expect me to do? I can't call America
racist without calling Americans racist.
And when I voiced this on my Instagram
people
really were upset at me because they
said that I was you know
trying to tank the campaign they said
that I was
really just being an angry crazy person
which I mean not Well, else is new?
Um
Being called an angry, crazy person. But
what I was genuinely
Perhaps I wasn't being as eloquent as I
could have been, but what I was
genuinely trying to do was to
to really get folks to understand their
own power. And that,
you know, we're going to need to make
demands.
Um And this is actually a really great
time to make demands because what we
don't understand as a populace is that
we are putting them in power and not the
reverse. And until we really, really,
really understand that, we are
continuing to play in a game where we
are not even We're We're like betting on
a game that we don't even know how to
play.
What was Kamala like in in person? Cuz I
I had my my criticisms of Kamala Harris
when she ran for president in 2020. When
I I looked at her record in California,
her criminal justice record is appalling
in my opinion. And for whatever reason,
she was advised to run
this campaign where let's just open our
arms and embrace
Liz Cheney. Let's brag about getting
money or support from Goldman Sachs. It
was the craziest thing that I had ever
seen. And I'm like, who came up with
this idea? But also, the situation with
Gaza. Her not willing to
separate herself from Joe Biden. As she
said on The View, she wouldn't do
anything differently. Like those types
of things. And now she has this book
tour where she's she's going around the
country talking about her book 107 days.
And I guess this is supposed to be her
redemption period. I I I I don't know.
But what was she like in person?
Was Was she laughing, Amanda? WAS SHE
LIKE
WAS SHE
NOW, NOW SABRINA.
Um
she was very well
this this interaction happened at Bloody
Sunday's commemoration in Selma
uh in February of 2024.
And um she heard I was there and had you
know summoned for me to come
to where she was in like a holding room.
And when I got there
uh there was you know a lot of people in
there and she was like so
hello.
And so there was an energy from the
beginning that was very much like oh
this is not you want to meet me this is
you want to confront me. Cuz you know I
was giving her the business on this
internet, right? As I FEEL IS MY JOB TO
DO.
I am a voter
um
and then I I said well to be quite I she
was she was like what do you want me to
do? And I said well I want you to be
different and I and she said well how
how can I how am I supposed to be
different? And I said well to be honest
I can't even talk to you the way I want
to talk to you with all these people in
here.
And so then she was like clear the room
clear the room. And so she cleared the
room.
And it was just me her and a
um
Secret Service agent.
And she was very uptight. I could tell
that she was very frustrated by
my pushback.
At the end of the interaction she was
like well
you know well we're going to talk
because I want to hear what you have to
say I want to hear what you have to say
we're going to talk. But then you know
and I shared I shared my information
with her team and they were like you
know she really wanted to meet you she
really wanted and I was like all right
well you know she was very testy but I
you know let's let's talk. And then um
but then 2 weeks later
I don't know if you remember this she
went to Puerto Rico. She Do you hear how
I just said that that was so US Ian? She
went to Puerto Rico.
She went to Puerto Rico.
And she had got off the plane and they
were singing
and clapping and she started clapping
along with them and then translator had
to tell her, "They're singing that
you're a colonizer. That's what they're
saying."
And she was like, "Huh?"
And
this would normally be a video that I
would make commentary about.
And I paused for a moment and was like,
"But if I do this video, maybe then they
won't want to talk to me."
And then I had to remember
that that's not what I'm here for.
I am not here to placate to politicians.
Um my value is in my
savviness. My value is in my willingness
to face things head-on. And so, I made
the video, and then a week later a smear
campaign began.
Um but what I want to add though is that
I think honestly, Savvy it Sabrina, it's
it's less about what Kamala is really
like.
And it's more about to me at this point
how distorted
the the the version of her has become by
the masses. Like, I just feel like
there's like a whole deifying that's
been happening
that is bizarre to me cuz I've never
seen it happen so fast. Because I know
folks was really not feeling her, and
then all of a sudden she was shot to
savior status.
And folks bought into that. And anyone
who questioned it was considered an op,
or I don't know if you were told that
you were a MAGA, or Yep. All the time,
right? Like, if you aren't voting for
her, you're voting for Trump. Um I never
see you talk about Trump. I had a radio
show on Radio One. I was talking about
Trump all
day long. I just think it's really
important that we talk about all of them
because none of them are here for us
until they will until they until we
force them to be.
Yeah, um I was called a a lot of names.
Um Roland Martin came after me. My
mother said that to me today. My mother
was like, you know Roland Martin I'd
come after Savvy Sage, YOU KNOW.
YEAH, HE HE CAME AFTER ME AND I told him
I said, you're welcome to come on my
show and have THE DISCUSSION BEFORE.
>> THING. DID he come?
No.
No, no, no, no. No. But I I I told
people early on, um, I don't care what
the polls are saying. I have talked to
people I'm in Massachusetts, I'm in a
blue state. I talked to people on the
ground. Most people told me they are not
coming out to vote. So I I was sounding
that alarm on the show for the whole
presidential election and everybody told
me, what do you know?
You you haven't been doing this long
enough. You don't know anything. You're
just a YouTuber. Roland Martin told me
he said, you're a YouTuber. I'm like,
you're a YouTube too. My name Like what
the It was It was It was wild.
That type of
That that that that type of elitism has
no place.
Because you know who's on YouTube?
Voters.
So, be where the people are. You know,
like for me, I was doing stand-up at the
time. So I'm in these clubs across the
nation and I'm doing stand-up but I was
also screening my documentary in Amanda
We Trust, which is literally about the
lack of civic engagement and civic
knowledge that's play that's here in
America in the United States and
if your version is people weren't voting
because they just didn't feel like it,
mine was everyone saying, I will not
vote for anyone who is supporting the
genocide in Gaza.
That's it's like there was no movement
on that and folks are like, that's a
single issue. So be it. Genocide is a
big enough issue to be a single issue
because it is an umbrella issue that has
several other issues under it.
And they didn't feel that that was
something worth bringing up and I think
that that was I not I think, I know that
that was a deeply
problematic move because even if the
even if the election was rigged,
which I do believe it was.
Um
In my opinion,
there's no room for politicians at this
point. You're either a public servant or
I have no energy for you.
Mhm.
You you are a representative of your
constituency.
You know, when I see Angie for Florida
putting on a mosquito net and a and a
uh
a windbreaker to go down to Alligator
Alcatraz, you know, and and beat on the
door to get in, that's the that's the
type of energy I'm trying to see.
All this performative nonsense, I've
been in show business since I was 8
years old. I can recognize some show
business savvy savs.
And a lot of these politicians are just
folks that couldn't read a script, so
they chose to read script
A lot of these politicians are just
people that couldn't read scripts and so
they chose to read speeches.
Mhm.
I I will say the Gaza issue was a really
big one.
Um and a lot of people, like I said, are
coming to me today and they're saying,
"See, you guys should have supported
Kamala Kamala Harris made it very clear
that she would not withhold any weapons
to Israel." She was very clear about
that. She was asked about that multiple
times and gave the same answer every
time. Then there was the Democratic
National Convention where there was a
Palestinian American that had a speech
that apparently was approved. She would
not allow them to come up on the stage
and and and speak, but she allowed the
Israeli family to come on the stage and
speak. I mean, there were multiple
opportunities. Then there's the I Am
Speaking Moment when she was at the
rally in Mich- in Michigan of all
places, which has the largest Arab
American population, a swing state. And
it just to me, it's like I feel like
people are putting on blinders, right?
They're like, "Well, this wouldn't be
happening in Gaza. The war wouldn't they
wouldn't be killing kids, they wouldn't
be starving kids if Kamala was
president. And I I honestly think that
they would. Because she said she
wouldn't withhold the weapons. So as
long as she's still giving them the
weapons, they're going to continue
killing people in Gaza.
I guess for me what's confusing is that
there's no history of Kamala Harris
being a rabble-rouser.
There's no history of Kamala Harris
going against the grain. There's no
history of Kamala Harris being
uh a rebel or being in resistance. So to
suggest that she would had she been in
office is is a false concept. It's
literally based on hopes, but not on
anything actual. And I think the other
thing we have to acknowledge is that she
has been in the establishment for a
really long time in service of
establishment. Like I saw someone say
the other day she used to lock bad guys
up as a DA. Well, anybody who actually
knows
the justice system knows that the DA is
not our friend, okay? Like and when I
say our, I mean black and brown people,
I mean the working class. The DA is
representing the country, okay? It says
the state versus or the United States
versus. And if you know the truth about
this nation, not about your ancestors,
right? Not about your black ancestors
who fought and died. That's not what I'm
talking about. When you know the truth
about the United States and you
understand the shift that the United
States made after World War II into
saying we're going to take over as the
biggest colonizers, I feel like that
has to somehow jog your thinking about
who signs up for that. And I think for a
lot of us
who have been really on the Democrat
boat,
we think
cuz I know this because I'm sure you get
this too. People say, "Well, then why
don't you run for office?"
If you have all the ideas, why don't you
run for office? We we think that being
in electoral politics
um
we think that that is a change-maker
move.
We think that's where change-makers go.
Even though look at all of these black
people behind me. We got James Baldwin,
we got Gil Scott-Heron, uh Angela Davis
is up there, you got Malcolm X. None of
them were in elected office. No. And all
of their messaging continues to resonate
and reverberate and drive many of us to
this day. So, to say that to me is
reductive.
Right. And that brings me to the
Democratic Party uh in general. And I
always
Dr. Cornel West will refer to them as
black faces in high places. There was
this episode recently on The Breakfast
Club where Charlamagne uh was talking
about Hakeem Jeffries. He's another one
that's a big AIPAC puppet. I thought
this was pretty interesting.
>> uh the speaker minority speaker Hakeem
Jeffries. Mhm. Because you know, I'm a
political nerd. Like I love talking
about politics.
>> Charlamagne hates him. You do? I don't
hate him. I just don't think he stands
for anything. I think I think that he's
I call him AIPAC Shakur. Well, we talked
We
We did talk about messaging. And I
actually went to the Capitol and had a
meeting with him. And we talked about
messaging and how I was like the
frustration with the party is y'all have
to get more gangsta. Like stop going by
the politics of the the late 2000s, you
know, and 2010. And you have to like
rise to the occasion in the messaging.
And he did. I saw him do more
afterwards.
>> Hakeem is a puppet. Hakeem's not doing
anything if Chuck Schumer don't tell him
to do it. And
That part right there. So, when you look
at people like Hakeem Jeffries, it's not
just Kamala. But when you look at people
like Hakeem Jeffries who takes a lot of
money from AIPAC. Uh Cory Booker is also
in that category. Someone shared this on
uh X, AIPAC Shakur and notorious IDF.
Yeah, like that was going to say he
didn't create that. That that that
that's been out there.
Yeah. So, what's like This is another
thing so I've been telling people I
think that we need to to move away from
the two-party system and organize on the
outside and building community and
building dual power.
One of the things we do at RBM we do a
lot of mutual aid, but whatever works
for you and and your community, but I
the problem that I continue to run into
is that a lot of in particular black
voters say that are you stupid? This is
how we ended up with Donald Trump. You
have to support the Democratic Party and
I point to people like Hakeem Jeffries
and Cory Booker who are basically black
faces in high places. Their number one
priority from what I've seen is to serve
and protect Israel, not really to do
anything for the black community. How do
you feel about that? How do you feel
about that organizing on the outside and
how do you get people away from that?
What do you say to people that think
that Hakeem Jeffries and Cory Booker are
like just the best thing ever?
It keeps me up at night, Sabrina.
Like trying to figure out what to say to
people. My homeboy Brandon who's a fan
of yours. Shout out to Brandon Victor
Dixon. He's who put me on to you.
Um, he was he once said he was like, you
know, there's all it takes is one sec is
one sentence to unlock someone's mind.
And I'm like, is it? Because I've been
I've been trying to find that sentence
for a long time.
Um, okay, so you said a lot. So let me
see. Um,
Well, one, let me just before we even
address them, let me just say this. If
you're saying anything about AIPAC, but
you're not saying free Palestine, you're
not really about it. So you don't get to
just play the political dance of AIPAC
without acknowledging that this is
really grounded in a colonizing effort
that is currently in a genocide
and has been. So I think that that was
actually like a very um
addressing of something that actually
needs to be addressed head-on.
Uh as for Hakeem Jeffries and Cory
Booker, I think anyone who loves them is
just a victim of not knowing what
they're really about. And they also
don't know what Israel is really about,
and that has been by design. You know,
we've we've really found ourselves in a
very unique time, right? Because the
shroud of secrecy and protection that
has come along with this whole you don't
say anything or you're an anti-Semite
has really held people back from knowing
the true incursion of Israel as a part
of this government. Really,
Israel is
a US outpost that serves as a
money-laundering
operation that brings dollars back into
the pockets of weapons US weapons
manufacturers and campaigns.
Um that's what Israel is. So, any
politicians that are engaging in the
support of Israel are engaging in the
theft of taxpayer dollars.
Whether they're black, whether they're
women, whether they're gay, if they are
uplifting Israel,
what they are doing, and this is not
nuanced. If they are uplifting Israel,
and if Israel is uplifting them, so
that's Jeffrey Bell, that's
uh what's his name, Torres, all of them.
They are absolutely involved in
corruption
and in the use of your hard-earned tax
dollars
to be funneled through and given back to
billionaires
and themselves. This is not some like
thing that I'm conspiracy theorizing. It
is what it is. However, we don't do that
math.
We don't follow those trails of money,
right? Like we don't That's what Drop
Site News and them That's what they live
for, right? Like that's what
Gray Zone News, they live to do that.
And our our people in the United States
are so busy trying to just live.
Yeah.
That it's really easier to just like
hang your hat on, "Nah, but they're cool
though. They look good in a suit." And
at the end of the day, it's two
light-skinned [ __ ] that are corny.
They They have no You know they can't
dance. And
um
they're the kind of They're the kind of
light-skinned [ __ ] that think they're
fine cuz they light-skinned. I know that
that's their vibe. That I know it.
And it's not the case.
Um
and
they again have no record, but there was
a reverence in Claudia's voice when she
said, "I went up there and I spoke to
him."
And I want us to really challenge
ourselves to stop pedestaling these
people. Yes.
I really want us to stop pedestaling
ourselves to stop I'm I really want us
to challenge ourselves to stop
pedestaling these people because they
are not in these positions based on
anything of merit. They're not based on
in these positions based on any standard
of um ethics of principles, right? Like
they got elected, but that's not just
because "Oh, but they were giving free
lunches You know like the the the the
cause of being elected has now become
some sort of like
gold star that supposedly means that you
deserved it." When we have seen
that that's not how things go. People
get elected because someone wants them
elected. Namely,
these
uh
these PACs that are not just AIPAC.
There's There's several Jewish PACS.
Yep. Zionist PACS. Let me be specific.
There's several Zionist PACS.
Yeah. Koufee.
J Street. There There's a number of
them. There's a number of them. And
some of y'all's favorites.
Some of y'all's favorites. I ain't even
going to say the names, but some of
y'all's favorites have said
"Well,
I'll take this money, but I'm not going
to do XYZ." And so, that
is them saying that I'm still in power.
And to be quite honest,
at this point, if you're not loud about
Palestine, I just don't I don't know.
You look concerned.
Who's the favorite?
>> I I'll text you that. Oh, boy.
Oh my gosh. Yeah, no, it's true because
um we've also seen people, you know,
Susan Sarandon, she's uh pro-Palestine.
She's been on the ground a lot of
protests. Even outside of like Gaza, she
was at a protest for Medicare for All.
Like, she's also an activist. Um we saw
people, particularly after October 7th,
that said they stood with the people in
Gaza, they were dropped from their
agencies. Like, Susan Sarandon was one
of those people that was dropped. Um
some people said they were blackballed I
was dropped.
>> because you were pro-Palestine.
Yeah.
I lost my publicist. I lost my agent. My
other agent, um we ended up going our
separate ways because he said that um
I said is he I asked him, "Are you
anti-Zionist?" And he was like,
"No."
And
I was like, "I mean, what do we What
There's This is not going to get better.
So, now I have someone negotiating for
me who I don't I can't really trust that
you're going to negotiate from, you
know, my best interest if you're putting
if you're being held to the fire. Um
and
uh
Yeah, I mean, I bought my book. My
memoir was supposed to come out later
this year.
And when I saw my editor's notes,
a number of her notes was was already
corny and sketchy, but then there was a
couple of notes that really showed me
that there was a presence of Zionism
that I had not
known before. Um
and she also like set me up to fail be
That's a longer story, but I ended up
buying the book back. And that was not
cheap. Um so
Very very very very very interesting. I
know another people they point out
Macklemore. They say, "Well, Macklemore
made these songs." Macklemore is
independent, so that is important for
people to know. Also, white boy is
Jewish.
There you go. I mean, when you're you're
independent, you can do those things.
Now, Amanda
>> canceled my shows last year. Like my
stand-up shows.
They was Sammy, I was in Detroit and
they had a truck outside of my show with
my face on the side of it that said
Amanda Seales is a Jew hater.
Wow.
Like they hacked my ticket site and so I
had to end up canceling my tour because
there was no way for me to sell the
tickets because every time people would
try and buy tickets, the site would get
messed up and people's tickets would all
types It was just like, "What are we
What are we going to do?" So, I ended up
just saying, "You know what? Screw it.
I'm just going to leave this entire life
behind because if they are if their only
way to really get to me is to do so by
trying to play with my money and play
with like my cuz that's like the whole
unlikable thing that went on last year.
Like all of that
all of that is coordinated. So, if their
goal to try and get to me like I saw
someone in your chat earlier today be
like, "Oh, she's she's trying to get us
to like her again." And I just want
folks to understand that when you go
through certain things in life, you
start to realize that all you need is to
like yourself.
Like you need to like yourself. And the
people who are supposed to be around you
are the ones who like that you like
yourself. And that has been one of the
greatest lessons ever because when these
people start coming for you, they're
coming for you para-psychologically,
they're coming for you economically. And
I said, "You know what? I'm going to do
free shows. I'm going to move. I'm going
to
simplify my lifestyle so I don't have
this level of overhead that I have to
still try to reach because so many
people will continue to
you know, equivocate and capitulate
because they they're trying to meet this
dollar amount. And I just said, "No."
So, that's why you see me
selling pins and artwork. That's why you
see me doing things very independently.
Like I have a one-woman show I've been
developing. I have a free show this uh
upcoming Saturday, this not this
Saturday, but the following Saturday,
the 6th at the the People's Forum.
And
many of us have had to do that to simply
just stand for humanity.
Yeah.
Yeah. And we've seen a a number of
people have been have been targeted.
Now, you just recently had this debate
on Jubilee.
And I got to ask cuz so many people have
talked about this debate. This young
gentleman right here, Amanda.
Uh the young gentleman who I I later
found out is from Maine. Um um
apparently
>> Angola.
And and yes. So, the I I'm just going to
play this part uh for those who have not
seen. Comparing Chinese people who are
immigrants that made a choice to come to
the United States and comparing the
continued effort of black people to
ground themselves in a nation that
continues to make impediments for them
to show and live and exist in their true
citizenship is a false equivalency.
>> I don't believe that happens at all.
What a what a No one here is in in I'm
telling the truth. There's no there's no
systemic racism that I've experienced
here in America. Um what system is
racist? I think the only racism that
we've actually seen recently, systemic
racism that we've seen, is the
application of systemic racism against
white people. The University of Western
Washington, for example, has been trying
to segregate dormitories using black
only dormitories because black people
feel safer amongst each other, but
they're more likely to kill each other
than white people are ever ever to kill
them. That's just the truth. You have
King Von rapping about killing other
black men. Why should I think that the
white man is the oppressor when black
men are more likely to kill me?
Tell me.
The big giveaway here, Amanda, I noticed
when he was talking about black people,
he kept saying they.
>> You guys and they. You guys and they.
And I was like, okay. Where where is
this So you say he's from Angola and I
guess he lives in Maine? Yeah, I don't
know if you got to watch the whole
thing, but I eventually like
was like, where are you from?
And he was like, well, I'm from Angola.
I said, where are your parents from?
Angola. And I'm like, well, when did you
move to the States? When I was 12. And
where did you move? To Maine. I was
like, get up.
I said, go sit down. You're not even
American.
And and and to be honest, it's not that
this conversation can't be had with
someone who's not American in terms of
like talking about what are things that
can be done to uplift black community in
America. We know that immigrants have
been a huge part of the fight for black
liberation in the United States. So that
is not the issue. The issue is when you
take the stance of judgment. The issue
is when you take the stance of insolence
and indignance and you are parroting
completely white nationalist talking
points that are meant to denigrate black
Americans. I mean, to suggest that, oh
well, it's more likely for black people
to harm other black people while not
referencing, you know, you You here and
reference King Von. So are we not going
to talk about that Ahmaud Arbery was
just running?
He was just on a jog. And and a and and
and a not only did this truck a white
man kill him, but then the DA got them
off like a whole system
cut a was allowed to ex- to to try to
excuse this man being killed. I mean,
George Zimmerman gets to walk around
free every day. You know, so this this
this is
simply just willful ignorance. And I let
him off easy just because he's a young
person. And those are the most, of
course, vulnerable minds.
So, one thing I I want to add is um so,
I'm I'm in Massachusetts in the Boston
area here. I go to Maine at least like
once once uh a summer. And uh Maine is
Maine is um
probably one of probably the most, I've
double-checked, but one of the widest
states in the United States. Uh on top
of that, on top of that, I had a student
who was from Maine who told me they were
not taught about black history in public
school because apparently in the state
of Maine, it is not required. And I
bring this up because this young man
went on to say later on that he doesn't
believe that redlining was real. My
parents grew up in a redlined
neighborhood in Baltimore, Maryland.
And this this this just really floored
me. I had to say to myself like, who is
teaching this guy? Like, where where is
he getting this information from? And
then the main thing and I was like, oh,
okay. Like, that makes a lot of sense.
But,
to your point about to your point about
immigration, after this debate, some
people saw this and they said they felt
like you changed your position on
reparations. And so, I just want to hear
from you like, where where do you feel
you stand today
um when it comes to reparations in the
United States?
Let me just put on record that y'all are
annoying. So, I just want to put that on
record. Um
So, this comes from this this whole
"Amanda doesn't think we should have
reparations." What this actually comes
from is that during the election season
of 2020, the run-up to the election,
there started to be a demand that in
order to vote for Joe Biden, he needs to
say that he's willing to give us
reparations.
And I was
at that time being swept up in the melee
of folks saying, "We can't ask for
things. It's too late in the game. We
just need to get him in office." So, I
became one of those mouthpieces that was
saying,
"You know, we can't make demands for
that right now. Like, we really just
need to get him in office. We just need
to get him in office. We just need to
get him in office. Like, you can't worry
about reparations right now." I I have
never said that black people don't
deserve reparations. I have never said
that reparations are not justified.
Um I think it's also
interesting that people have very strong
stances about what they think my stance
is who do not follow me.
So, they are either getting my stance
via somebody else or through clips that
they may have taken in years ago. And my
stance was made very clear in the video.
My stance was made very clear in the
reparations project I did with the
reparations project.
Um
And I continue to stand on what I've
always stood on, which is that
reparations are owed
over a multitude of reasons, not just
slavery. Like, reparations are owed
locally,
on a city level, on a state level, on a
county level. Reparations are owed on a
national level. I am also from the
Caribbean. Reparations are owed to the
Caribbean from Britain and the other
countries that are still colonizing. So,
this is this is a moot point that people
are trying to People just want to have a
reason to for some reason undermine my
relevance. And I don't know what that
is, and I think that's a conversation
that some of y'all should have
honestly with yourselves. Like, what is
it that makes me constantly look for
a way to make Amanda Seales's point of
view not valid?
Why why am I always looking for that?
And ask yourselves, do you do that with
other people?
Well, here's Well, here's one of the
questions from Devotion Orange. Can you
ask Amanda how she came to be a part of
the reparations discussion without
mentioning the [ __ ] movement? The [ __ ]
movement has been uh harassing me and
attacking me for the past how many
years, telling me that I'm a coconut,
that I need to go back to Grenada,
telling me that I am not black American,
even though I am the descendant of
shadow slavery in the United States, and
that I literally my great great great
grandmothers
uh the birth certificate for her
daughter is also signed by her slave
owner. So, it's like deeply insulting,
um and I just don't think that the
conversation about reparations should be
solely attached to being a descendant of
slavery, because we know that black
people in the United States have
suffered at the hands of racism and
legislation and institutionalization of
racism in more ways than one. So, yes,
there is reparations owed to American
descendants of slavery. There are also
reparations owed to individuals who were
not able to get property and land and
redlined out of those spaces. There is
reparations owed to people. I believe
there's reparations owed to the people
who are still locked up right now on
marijuana charges.
In places where marijuana is no longer a
criminal offense. And you have actually
Ashy and Ashy C with a marijuana
dispensary while you know, Tyree and
Latif are still doing time. Because of a
three strikes law that Joe Biden helped
to push. So,
uh you know, when it comes to [ __ ] I
think that there are certain members of
the [ __ ] community who really are simply
just saying I am a descendant of
American slavery. But, when I see a lot
of the mouthpieces of [ __ ] of [ __ ] who
really are at the forefront of the
movement,
it feels more exclusionary than
inclusionary. And I don't think that is
useful as a Pan-Africanist.
Well, I've interviewed some on the show.
Um and there's things there's places
where I agree and there's places where I
disagree. But, one thing I will say, you
know, when I talk about reparations, I
do make that distinction because of the
legality and the debt that's owed. So,
that is one of the things that I do uh
discuss on the show is that uh
reparations in the United States is owed
to those who are the descendants. Uh and
that's based on the debt that is owed,
that 40 acres and a mule. Um I just
don't want people to confuse it with
like racial injustice. Um but, I also
tell people I do believe that
reparations are owed to Haiti from
France. Uh like you said, you mentioned
Britain. I believe that as well. But, I
think that when we look at the legality
of it,
we can't say
>> argued that. I mean, I literally just
said that. Yeah, I think that's I think
that maybe the impression that some
people had. That's not an impression.
That is an expression.
That's not I'm I'm not saying anything
counter to that. They just see a
Grenadian flag behind me, and I have a
Grenadian mother, and so that for some
reason to them means that I should not
be speaking about reparations as if I do
not have the blood of United States
slaves in my body.
Malcolm X's mother was also from
Grenada.
So I
you know, again, it's that's not I I
haven't said anything to the to the
otherwise. If you are a descendant of
slavery, you should be given reparations
for slavery.
There should also be reparations
discussed as it relates to the to the
property and the complete stonewalling
of black people from obtaining
generational wealth.
We were supposed to be given 40 acres
and a mule and then 2 days later they
took it back after they murdered
Lincoln.
Yeah. Um I talked to Dr. Darity about
that on the show before, too.
Um and he he broke down like a lot of
numbers. And it's one of those things,
but why do you feel it's taboo? I feel
like I feel like when you bring it up or
when anyone brings it up, it's very
taboo. Even on the left.
Mhm? Reparations?
Mhm.
Um because I think that we don't realize
that we've really been pacified.
You know, we've been pacified into like,
here [ __ ] damn.
In my show, what would the ancestors
say, I have a whole section about here
[ __ ] damn cuz that's basically how
anything that has been given to black
people in this country has been given to
us.
Here [ __ ] damn. Civil rights, fine.
You guys are always asking for [ __ ]
Damn. Like even in Eric Foner, white
white white man Eric Foner's
Reconstruction
book classic book on the reconstruction,
he talks about how
the United States was like over it.
20 years after the Emancipation
Proclamation, they was like, this is
just too hard. We we just going to go
backwards. So
um I think that we we really don't
realize how we've been pacified by
capitalism. We don't realize how after
the civil rights movement, you did have
a a whole groundswell of of political
awareness and of black power movement
and the the the
not just the black power movement of the
Black Panthers, but you also had like
cultural power movements within the
Chicano movements, within you know, the
Asian communities, etc. There was
coalition building and
there was also
a very concerted effort to replace
resistance with excellence.
And this idea of like if you can
assimilate into
what you now were not able to get to,
then that will be your safety. And
that's what I believe Sinners was really
all about saying that like assimilation
will not
save us.
And then I look at the other side, too.
Cuz I want this I want him to to finish
here cuz I want people to hear this,
like what he said. This is scary. You
need to think about me as your mama. Do
not talk to me in that fashion. They
definitely cut
that out
of that, by the way.
>> They they edited this? Yeah, they edited
that. Cuz it looks as if he didn't say
anything to be a catalyst for me to
respond that way when he did.
So, Oh, okay.
>> he had been to he had got he was getting
real comfortable and real
talking to me like we on the playground
and that's why I had to be like, "Whoa,
whoa, whoa. Let's bring it down. Let's
bring it down."
Interesting.
On a basic level, we have to understand
that systemic racism is grounded in the
realities that black people have not
been considered an equal human being in
this country since its onset. So,
there's simply no way to make the
argument that there isn't systemic
racism and we have seen in very clear
ways the system operate in or in an
organically racist way. Do not cut me
off. When we talk about systemic racism,
we can start with even the fact that
redlining, which was implemented to
discriminate black communities. Are you
shaking your head that redlining doesn't
exist? No. I I'm saying that I don't
think it really existed at all. I mean,
no, I don't think so at all. So, it does
exist, and stating that it doesn't exist
doesn't make it no longer exist.
Redlining absolutely exists. It is not a
It is not something that's being made
up. It's an empirical fact, and there
are realities that exist because of
redlining. We know that school systems
are related to the way that property
taxes are affecting the school systems.
If a school system is not getting the
same property value as the property
taxes allow it, then it's not going to
have the same efficacy at allowing for
students to be able to get what they
deserve. When we talk about systemic
racism, we have to acknowledge that
these private prisons are literally
built based on the test scores of school
students in third grade. So, if you are
literally building prisons with the
onset of, "Okay, if these people are not
reaching a certain reading level, then
we know that they're going to go down a
prison industrial pipeline, where we can
use their free labor." Then, how is that
not systemic? And if you And if you want
us to Stop them from entering prisons.
How are you going to stop people from
entering prisons if your goal if your
goal is to get them into prison?
>> Sure. Make them try to be more like Ben
Carson than be like King Von. That's
very very simple. So
So, I had to pause there because the Ben
Carson part really got to me. Um First
of all, I I I don't know who is big on
Ben Carson. What?
It's funny. They They want to mention
Ben Carson. Uh Ben Carson tried to stab
uh uh his brother. I Do Do people know
this? I did not know that. Yeah, Ben
Carson tried to stab his brother. Uh Ben
Carson, as as much as conservatives say,
um no handouts
in reference to welfare, Ben Carson's
mom was on welfare at one point. See,
these are the things that they leave out
um of the conversation. But, what was
really interesting to me, when you went
into this debate, did you know the
people who the people were going to be
that you would face? No.
I didn't know anything, and they didn't
know that I was going to be who they
were facing.
They were also told that I was a
liberal.
Even though I was very abundantly clear
that I am a black radical.
Wow. Yeah, I got sidelined. I got I got
blindsided by that. So,
um
like three by by like the fourth person,
I was like, "Why do y'all keep
saying to me like liberal this, liberal
that?" And then the fourth person came
up, and she was like, "Well, just so you
know, people keep saying that because
they told us that you were a liberal.
They told us that we were going to be
debating a liberal."
Um
and um so, no, I don't know and I I just
think that I don't I don't think anyone
really understands what it is to be in
this type of situation.
Cuz there's nothing that really prepares
you
for this. Because
had they been white folks, I wouldn't
have done it. Let's start with that.
Cuz that would have just been
sensationalist.
I wanted to do this with black folks.
One, I thought they were going to have
actual salient points.
And not and like even if their points
were able to be challenged and debunked,
like I I just thought that they would
have kind of
um points that were grounded more in
even if it was data or or their version
of facts. But really, it was a lot of
people just saying, "Well, my uncle and
my cousin, my mom's cousin, and um you
know, I I did this, so why can't anybody
do that?" Uh so, and and again, debates
typically have rules, and there's no
rules to this, right? So,
you know, there was like
me trying to be fair and let them talk.
And then when I would talk back,
they would then talk over me because
they've been instructed,
even if it's not directly, they've been
instructed by the content
to just yell over each other, right?
Like And so there were four different
points in the taping. They didn't show
this, but there were four different
points in the taping where I stopped the
whole thing and said like, "I need y'all
to understand I'm not your enemy.
I'm not here to fight you."
And by the third, by the fourth time,
well, no, the third time, I went we we
had a break, I came back, I led them in
a
group deep breath, I led them in a
primal scream.
I wanted them to understand that
the goal of this is to demonstrate
discourse.
It's to demonstrate disparate discourse,
civil discourse. Um and then by the last
time, I said, you know,
"Nobody on the crew is black.
There ain't one black person over there.
We're over here in this fishbowl.
And we can't even have
a respectable conversation grounded in
facts about our own community. What does
that say?"
And I think to them, they thought what I
was saying was that we're like, you
know,
uncivilized, but really what that says
is that we have been infiltrated.
That's what that says.
And for those who don't understand why I
did this,
um
I honestly wanted to be able to, one,
demonstrate civil discourse, but I also
wanted to be able to demonstrate being
something other than a Democrat or a
Republican while still having a deep,
grounded, fact-based love for being
black,
for being in in the quest of liberation,
and for understanding that there's going
to be folks that have already been
colonized. Their minds like black people
in this nation have been the most useful
resource of this nation. We beyond our
physical labor, now they're using our
mental labor to push their policies to
literally push us backwards. They're
weaponizing us. We're seeing black ice
agents. We're weaponizing our
identities. I'm seeing black
conservative influencers that I know
don't believe what they're saying. But
they can get a bag.
They can get a bag and they've decided
that that's fine.
You know, for me and my connection to my
ancestors, that's not fine. But um
you know, that's I I So no, I didn't
know anything going in.
And uh the only thing I knew when I left
was that I would never do it again.
Yeah, it's for people who don't know,
they had another episode which I did not
watch and I will not
called black men versus black women.
What?
>> That Yes. Yes. But what was the
What's the verses?
I I didn't watch it.
>> Yeah, it's gender.
>> that was just
Black men versus black women.
So the other part of this Sabri Sabrina
is that they're in LA.
And I'mma tell you now, people will just
sign up to be anything because they want
to get seen. So many people have left
wherever they're from to come here to
make it, right? To come to LA to make
it. To for a lot of people, they're just
like this is a part that I'm playing.
People to this day still think I am
Tiffany from Insecure.
Like they really think that that's my
personality.
Yeah, it's it's it's sad. I was I when I
saw that I was like, okay, they're going
far and and and beyond. Amanda, one more
thing I do want to ask you,
um
moving away from like politics and we
talk about movement building and
organizing, one of the things that my
producer Eric always says is that we
need to have concrete demands. So, he
created this
platform here called 11 demands. Mhm.
Real change starts with demands, health
care for all, a minimum standard of
living for everyone, end the wars,
um MCDS, which stands for money,
corruption, demands, and solution.
Follow the money, call out the
corruption, have robust demands, dial
them up to 11. Good demands lead to good
solutions. And there's a a number of
them. He shortened it for us.
>> So, Eric is a socialist is what you're
telling me.
Eric
I don't know if Eric Eric labels himself
as a socialist or not, but when you go
through the 11 demands, one of those
demands is also for people who ask is
also reparations. One of the things that
Eric has continued to point out is that
and we say it on the show, politicians
are not heroes and they're not going to
save you.
What I seemed to have noticed it seemed
like in 2024, there was a a window for
people to go in a different direction,
for people to either vote third party or
maybe focus on organizing because of
both parties were supporting like a
genocide, etc.
And what I become to notice, now we're
hearing more people talk about a general
strike and those of us at RBN, we talked
about it like three three and a half
years ago. We had a general strike
summit.
Do you believe that it could be possible
to build a movement around 11 demands,
something that is outside of politics?
One of the things I worry about is I I
look at some of the things from the past
like the BLM movement which got became
co-opted. Um I I look at successful ones
like the civil rights movement or like
the women's movement and then I I learn
about CIA infiltration in those
movements as well. Do you think it's
possible in this day and age we could
have another massive movement that is
outside of electoral politics that
actually gets working class people some
type of win?
Yes.
I believe that
the one of the biggest reasons why the
CIA was able to infiltrate
>> straight
so effectively into these uh movements
for liberation
was because they were dealing with
people that were deeply unhealed.
The trauma that they were fighting, they
were continuously still living and still
experiencing.
And there is something that has happened
in the past I would say 10 years where
there has been, you know, a surge of of
wellness and care, self-care within
particularly the black community that
just didn't exist before, particularly
with black women, right? People are
like, you know, doing Beyoncé meditation
sessions, etc. Um
that mindfulness is imperative to
healing. I saw that there's a school in
Baltimore that has stopped sending kids
uh away for suspension and instead
brings them into meditation for
suspension and is teaching them, you
know, tools for managing their emotions,
language for managing their emotions,
right? So what I'm trying to say is
one of the tools that those folks didn't
have, we have.
And we have to make
mindfulness
and actual psychological strengthening
through healing
the the 12th
demand. We have to have mental health as
an integral part of our revolution.
Mhm.
We are still I just had these two dope
brothers um
David Turner the third and Eric Morrison
Smith of the Alliance for Men and Boys
of Color in LA on Views from AmandaLand.
And they were talking about coalition
building and they were like, you know,
coalition building is it's necessary and
it's it's integral, but it's really
really difficult
because we're dealing with folks,
particularly black folks, that have gone
through trauma. And so we have trust
issues, we have a fear of vulnerability.
And so he said, you know, we actually
end up doing a lot of rapport building
before we're even able to get to the
work, right? And so that intimacy is
where I believe our ability to win is
going to live. That intimacy is
completely disintegrated on this
internet on a daily basis. The
willingness for folks to engage in
toxicity, I'm guilty of it, too, is
absolutely an is absolutely an
impairment to our ability to our own uh
liberation. It's it's it's it's by
design. If we're busy
releasing that chemical into our bodies,
we are not doing the work that can
actually get
get these chemicals out of our air
because, you know, the AI
stuff that they're doing is actually
messing up our ability to breathe as
well. So, that to me is possible to
answer your question. I think that even
the from what I've seen of the few
demands, they seem completely possible
and pertinent. However,
I don't know that enough people are
willing to admit
the the evil that we're facing
because
it feels like it's like supernatural.
So, I want to just land the plane
and I want to I want y'all to know like
we're dealing with addicts.
We're dealing with people who are
addicted to money and power.
And
if you've ever dealt with addicts,
you know that there is, you know, an
insatiable appetite for that which
feeds them.
But they're basically the White House
and the Hill is like a crack house.
They're all just sharing the pipe of
power.
And so it's going to take us as a people
doing our best to get clear-headed
and to get to stay clean
and not engage in in their in their pipe
pipe passing
um
to be of any value. And until we're
willing to understand that, we're not
going to get anywhere.
In between the White House and the Hill
is a crack house. Well, Amanda,
thank you so much for your time. Uh
anything you got coming up that you want
to promote?
Yes, you guys can watch my show Views
from AmandaLand every Wednesday at 10:00
a.m. Eastern at YouTube Amanda Seales
TV. And I'm doing a residency every
first Saturday of the month at the
People's Forum with uh my one-woman show
What Would the Ancestors Say? And I'm
also doing a summit at the People's
Forum September 19th, 20th, and 21st.
It's the AmandaLand Summit. And though
we have registrations that are filled,
we're keeping it small to 50 people.
There will be two events two events that
will be open to the public. One will be
an event called Cracking Up the System.
It's a panel that combines two socially
conscious uh comedians with two
organizers. So, we have Davidson Boswell
and comedian Christina Brown, and they
will be in conversation with organizers
Angie Langdon and uh Claudia de la Cruz.
So, that's going to be a fun time. And
uh then that evening we will have a live
recording of my show Views from
Amandaland, which the guests are TBD.
So, hopefully you guys can come out to
that, and you can also always subscribe
to my Patreon, which is the best way to
support me. And if you want to get some
some of my goods, some of my art, you
can go to amandalandexports.com.
That was a lot of promoting. That's a
lot.
Awesome. Amanda, thank you thank you so
much for your time, and I'm glad we were
able to connect. Thank you, too. And I
hope that you'll come on to Views from
Amandaland.
Let me know. All right. We got We got
each other's info now, so it's going to
happen. Have a good night, y'all.
Bye.
Hey guys, this was a Savvy clip. If you
like what you saw, hit that like button
and subscribe.